Check the film on that kid.
AL: Take a deep breath.
Inhale. exhale. Again.
Slowly.
RICHARD: [Whispers] Check the film.
AL: Take it easy.
What's the status on that kid?
AL: Possible fractured sternum.
ANNE: Get over here. I need you.
Can you help us?
Bring this kid to Observation Room Two.
Yeah. you. Come on. help us out. okay?
How are you. champ?
My chest hurts.
Does it hurt when you breathe?
BO Y: Yes.
RICHARD: What's your name?
JOEL: Joel.
Look at this.
SAM: We're eating oranges
and we're making IDs.
"C.C.H." What the hell is that?
Cook County Hospital.
RICHARD: Just hang on. okay?
You'll be okay. pal.
You'll be just fine.
Hold that elevator.
Thank you.
RICHARD: How're you doing?
My chest hurts.
Where's your mom. pal?
I don't know.
Is she at home?
I think she's with my brother.
Your brother? They're downstairs?
JOEL: I don't know.
Don't worry.
We'll find her for you.
RICHARD: What are you?
Football player? Baseball player?
JOEL: Football.
Hold on. son.
Hey. Doctor.
They sent this one from downstairs.
Get this one into Room Four. stat.
RICHARD: Bye-bye. Joel.
Where's that boy I sent here?
GLADYS: What boy?
ANNE: The one with the fractured sternum.
He never came through here.
He didn't?
No. he didn't.
Do you have a particular interest
in our patient's X-rays?
What do you mean?
I saw you looking at that boy's chest film.
- It's a hobby of mine.
- It's a hobby. really?
What's your other hobby. brain surgery?
What do you want?
To know how that boy got to surgery.
I'm a janitor. I do as I'm told.
That's bullshit!
Who changed those orders?
I don't know what you mean.
You stay right there.
ANNE: Call Security!
ANNE: Hey! Hey!
RICHARD: Excuse me.
[Tires screech]
[Siren wails]
Tell Stevens to get hold of
that guy Kelly over at C.P.D.
A guy disguised as a janitor orders
an emergency medical procedure...
...and all you did was
take away his I.D. Card?
No. I called Security. He took off down
the hall. What was I supposed to do?
Listen. Mr...
SAM: Deputy.
Gerard.
I'm really tired.
I'd like to go home now.
Okay. How's the boy doing?
He saved his life.
Thank you.
"Desmondo. José Ruiz."
Where're you at. Desmondo?
Okay. Sam. this is my problem.
The place is crawling with cops. right?
Everybody's looking
for Richard Kimble. right?
So why would a guy be stupid enough...
...to hang out in the trauma ward
and play Mother Teresa?
Excuse me.
You. guys. have a problem?
No.
No. no. No problem at all.
SAM: Excuse me. could we
have a word with you. please?
This is Dr. Elway at Cook County Hospital.
I'm following-up for the prosthetic clinic
on Matthew Zelick.
Oh. he did?
I'm terribly sorry.
Right or left?
Right.
SAM: Age?
POOLE: 35 to 45.
This is Ted Riley
with the High School Reunion Committee.
25 years are right around the corner...
...and Clive is on our list
of missing in action.
The information gave me a number.
but when I tried it...
No kidding.
Armed robbery?
He's where?
Point of attachments?
Mid-humerus.
That gives us 47 possibles.
47?
Robert. cross-check these people
for criminal records.
BIGGS: Wait a minute.
[Motor boat revving]
[Bagpipes blare. marching drum plays]
MEGAPHONE: Happy St. Patrick's Day
to all of you.
[Elevator bell rings]
COP: Hey there. what's happening?
BIGGS: Driscoll. Clive R.
BIGGS: One-armed man. armed robbery.
That's funny.
BIGGS: Question:
BIGGS: If they can dye
this river green today...
...why can't they dye
it blue the other days?
Biggs. how do I know?
HENRY: So. what are you Irish. sir?
SAM: Who. me? No.
SAM: Are you?
HENRY: No. man!
Name of inmate?
Clive Driscoll.
Driscoll. Clive.
I.D.. please.
Driscoll. Clive R.
2- 0-1-0.
Be advised that under federal court ruling.
your conversation can be recorded.
Sign here. please!
This is hinky. He is a college graduate.
He wouldn't go through all this security...
...go to the county lock-up to find
someone his own people say doesn't exist.
Hinky.
What does that mean. "hinky"?
BIGGS: Strange.
HENRY: Weird.
Say "strange" or "weird."
"Hinky" has no meaning.
Why not say "hinky"?
I don't want you using meaningless words
around me. I'm taking the stairs.
How about "bullshit"?
Visitor for Driscoll.
Come on. let's go. let's go.
GUARD: Over there.
[Exhales deeply]
[Woman and inmate speaking in Spanish]
GUARD: Let's go. Driscoll.
GUARD: You've got five minutes.
Who the hell are you?
Look. I'm sorry. I made a mistake.
CLIVE: You got me down here...
...might as well talk.
Down here you got no entertainment.
Ain't no cable here.
Listen. pal. I wish I could. but I can't.
Sorry.
Richard!
Officer. there is a man in a blue coat
waving a gun and screaming... at a woman.
SAM: Stop that man!
HENRY: He's a U.S. Marshal! Let him go!
HENRY: Let him go!
SAM: Close the gates!
[Woman screams]
[Buzzer ringing at gates]
SAM: Hold it!
[Loud multiple gunshots]
[People screaming]
SAM: Open the doors!
We're on the roof.
BIGGS: Take some men! Look down there!
Jesus. he's in the plaza. Sam!
He's heading east!
BIGGS: He's going east
toward the Picasso!
[Wings fluttering]
[Marching band. bagpipes playing]
[Announcements over megaphone.
whistles blowing. crowd noise]
[Cymbals crashing]
[Bagpipes blaring]
MEGAPHONE: Happy St. Patrick's Day
to all of you.
[Snare drums building.
playing loud march]
[Whistles blowing]
Deputy Gerard. why do you feel
that Dr. Kimble came back to Chicago?
I have no idea.
We understand your deputies
were at the hospital today.
Was Dr. Kimble at the hospital?
I don't have any comment on that one.
Let me get the chronology straight.
The subject was tried.
convicted. incarcerated...
...escaped. presumed dead. and is now
at large in Chicago. Is that correct. sir?
Except for being presumed dead.
Do you believe that Kimble's
armed and dangerous?
KELLY: I believe he's dangerous. yes.
He's taking chances. coming back. Do you
feel that perhaps he might be innocent?
No. he's not innocent. He was convicted
in a court of law. He's guilty.
REPORTER: How will you try to catch him?
SAM: We have no further comments
for now.
[Propellers pelting]
[Blues music playing. ambient bar noise]
[Phone ringing]
[Dog barking in distance]
[Shattering]
[Dog howling in distance]
[Dance music playing]
Alec.
Richard Kimble.
RICHARD: Hi. how are you.
ALEC: Good. Dr. Kimble.
Lentz!
ALEC: Sorry. we've been trading phone
calls the last few days.
MAN: A cruise sponsored by
Devlin MacGregor...
... that could be fun.
- Cancún. Richard.
- Sport fishing.
Piña coladas.
What must the hospital buy?
What's the catch?
Sailfish.
No. there are no strings attached.
So what do you say? So what do you say?
RICHARD: This guy is bleeding from
every needle puncture.
STEVENS: Lentz sent this guy in?
Is he on that wonder drug?
Yes. he's on the RDU-90 protocol. Provasic.
RICHARD: Drug of the future. boys.
RICHARD: Clean out those arteries
and put us out of business.
"Parade Master of Ceremonies
Ed O'Flaherty said...
"...he didn't recall a livelier parade
during the last 20 years.
BIGGS: "That Kimble...
"...is some kind of lad..."
SAM: "Lad?"
BIGGS: Yeah. "lad."
BIGGS: Maybe he's a leprechaun.
I'm quoting this guy.
Some guy on line three claims
he's Richard Kimble.
BIGGS: Who is it?
COSMO: We got another Kimble
on line three.
Henry. let me see that phone.
BIGGS: Tell him he looks good in a beard.
NEWMAN: What line?
SECRETARY: Three.
BIGGS: "I hope he was able to wear
a little green. sip some whiskey..."
[Chuckling] This is Gerard.
Do you remember what I told you
in the tunnel?
POOLE: It's him!
SAM: I remember it was noisy.
Well. I think you said something like...
...you didn't kill your wife.
Remember what you told me?
I remember you were pointing
my gun at me.
You said. "I don't care."
[Whispering] He's on the south side.
Yeah. Richard. that's right. I don't care.
I'm not trying to solve a puzzle. here.
Well. I am trying to solve a puzzle.
Five seconds to location.
And I just found a big piece.
Richard...
Richard?
SAM: Richard? Richard?
SAM: Hello. Richard?
He didn't hang up the phone.
Where is he?
256 South St. Lawrence.
Get the C.P.D. Right the hell over there.
POOLE: We got a car there now.
[Tires screeching]
[Dog barking]
Get a couple of shots of that.
POOLE: Fredrick Sykes...
...45. ex-cop. and quite a clotheshorse.
Deputy. you want to look at this?
Yeah.
Kimble's prints. They're all over...
...but mainly on the desk.
He sure had some interest
in these photographs.
SAM: Negatives in there?
SAM: Let me have them.
BIGGS: Camera boy's on his way.
HENRY: We got you.
How're you doing. Mr. Sykes?
SYKES:
Fine. if you tell me what's happening.
BIGGS: We had a problem.
SYKES: My place or the place upstairs?
BIGGS: Your place.
ROSETTl: Step right in. Mr. Sykes.
Everybody knows my name here.
Big happy family. huh?
SYKES: What is this. a trench coat
convention? What the hell is going on?
SYKES: Who are you guys?
What's going on?
You had a break-in. Mr. Sykes.
I sure hope you're a cop.
No. I'm Samuel Gerard.
United States Marshal's Office.
SAM: This morning a fugitive named
Kimble made a phone call from here.
Why would he do that?
I don't know any Richard Kimble.
Okay. I got it.
The doctor who killed his wife. right?
Keep blaming somebody with
a prosthetic limb. Is he coming after me?
Does he have reason to do so?
I have a prosthetic arm! I must've done it!
SYKES: Give me a break.
I went through all this a year ago.
I was questioned here
about the whole thing.
I told them I wasn't in Chicago
on that night. I was on a business trip.
15 people verified it.
What line of business are you in.
Mr. Sykes?
Security.
SAM: Who do you work for?
SYKES: A pharmaceutical company.
Which one?
Devlin MacGregor.
I handle security for all the top executives.
Do you have any idea why Kimble would
be interested in these photographs?
No.
Where were they taken?
Gee. that's a big fish!
SYKES: Cancún. Mexico.
It was a junket the company
paid for some doctors.
SAM: Kimble go with you?
SYKES: You don't see him there. do you?
No. I told you I don't know him.
SYKES: Do you mind if I look around to see
if anything's missing?
No. I don't mind.
How'd you lose that arm?
In the line of duty.
[Birds chirping]
[Sam sighs deeply]
Cosmo. this guy's dirty.
COSMO: Yes. he is.
COSMO: You want our people on him?
SAM: Yes. Build a camp here.
SAM: Henry?
HENRY: I'll take care of it.
Noah? See this picture? I want you
to find out who's the guy next to Sykes.
Find out his name. his age. his weight.
his social security number...
...his location. relatives. pets. everything.
[Whispering] I am so sorry. Doctor.
they said it was an emergency.
Thank you. Excuse me.
[Phone rings]
CHARLES: Mr. Bolton.
Chuck.
CHARLES: Richard.
Yeah. can you talk?
Yes. I'm on a hotel phone.
So how are you? What's going on?
I found him. Chuck.
I found the man who killed Helen.
CHARLES: What?
RICHARD: It was me they were after.
Who are they?
Devlin MacGregor and Lentz.
Lentz was supervising
the protocol for RDU-90.
He knew I found out it was causing liver
damage. It was Lentz.
Richard. Lentz is dead.
What? How?
CHARLES:
He died in a car accident last summer.
Can you prove this about the drug?
Yeah. I think so.
I need your help. Chuck.
Call Bones at the hospital.
Tell him to give me whatever help I need.
I'll call him now.
Okay. Thanks.
MAN: Dr. Nichols...
CHARLES: Hey. how are you?
Dr. Nichols!
SAM: Can we ask you
a few more questions?
Mr. Gerard.
You got a copy of that photograph?
SAM: U.S. Marshal Service.
Excuse us.
This is Fredrick Sykes.
He's a security specialist
at Devlin MacGregor Pharmaceuticals.
Richard Kimble broke into his apartment.
Do you know this man?
No. I don't know him.
You're getting pretty desperate.
aren't you. Mr. Gerard?
Oh. yeah.
I told you. you wouldn't find Richard.
SAM: Has he been to see you?
CHARLES: No.
We've been over this ground before.
haven't we?
Yeah.
CHARLES: So. if you'll excuse me.
SAM: Sure.
SAM: Thanks. Doc.
COSMO: Thank you. Doctor.
Sorry. I want to ask you
one more question about the photograph.
See the guy standing
on the right side of the fish?
Ever see him before?
This guy right here?
I've never seen that person
in my life before.
SAM: Okay.
CHARLES: I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Thank you. Doctor.
Enjoy the rest of the convention.
"Alternatives to Cardio-Non-Invasive
Arterial Plaque-Reducing Therapy.
"Keynote speaker. Charles Nichols."
Bet they line up to hear this one.
[Siren wails]
If you were Richard Kimble...
...why would you hunt for a one-armed
man you say killed your wife...
...break into his house.
call us up and then split?
I should have been a doctor.
NEWMAN: Look at this blow-up. This guy
in the picture with Sykes. On his shirt.
NEWMAN: Chicago Memorial.
I want to go there.
SAM: Go!
BIGGS: Wait.
Devlin MacGregor...
...did 71/2 billion dollars in net sales...
...last year alone.
That company is a monster.
[Phone rings]
Yeah. talk to me.
Absolutely.
RICHARD: It's a liver sample...
... from a patient on the RDU-90 drug study.
RICHARD: 21. January 21st?
BONES: The last one!
1-7-4-3-0?
1-7-4-3-0. You got it.
Thanks. Bones. I'll make sure
all this stuff gets back to you.
RICHARD: It's good to see you again.
BONES: Good to see you.
BONES: So whatever happened
to that thing with your wife?
It's not over yet.
[Siren wailing. horn blows]
Hey. Rosetti. What's going on?
How should I know?
I think his name is Alec Lentz.
A pathologist.
I remember because he died last summer.
Oh. my God. Richard!
What are you doing here?
Hi. Kath.
KATHY: Have a look.
KATHY: What do you think?
RICHARD: Cold normal.
Clearly not the same tissue.
And not only did they all
come from healthy livers...
...they all came from the same liver.
Kath. you beauty.
[Bones humming to himself]
NEWMAN: Excuse me.
NEWMAN: Mr. Roosevelt?
I am Deputy Biggs. this is
Deputy Newman. We're U.S. Marshals.
Need some information about a Dr. Lentz
who was on staff here.
I want to know if he knew or had
had any contact with a Dr. Richard Kimble?
I haven't seen Dr. Kimble.
I didn't ask that.
I wouldn't know.
If you'll excuse me.
I have prior obligations to attend to.
NEWMAN: I think you're lying to us.
You think Lentz is the bad guy?
Yeah. why not?
He was one of the original
patent boys in RDU-90.
I was sending in my tissue samples...
...he was replacing them with healthy
samples. issuing the path reports...
...shit-canning my stuff. Easy.
KATHY: Wait a minute.
Lentz died August 21st.
Half the samples he approved
were signed the day he died.
You're kidding.
Someone else must have been
manipulating this.
Someone with access.
Thanks. Kath.
Where're you going?
To see a friend.
This is giving me a headache.
That's surprising. Where did
Roosevelt say Kimble was going?
He says he doesn't know.
SAM: Do you believe him?
NEWMAN: Yes. I do.
NEWMAN: He says he was here to pick up
some tissue samples...
... for a drug study.
But listen. get this.
The release was approved
by Dr. Charles Nichols.
NEWMAN: Nichols also knew Lentz.
NEWMAN: He was Lentz's boss.
He was covering for Kimble.
Send the C.P.D. Over there right now.
We're going to send a bunch of cops.
Make sure they turn that place inside out.
Don't let them give you shit
about your ponytail either. Well done.
My pleasure. Sam.
Henry. Dr. Nichols lied to me.
SAM: Go find him.
HENRY: I'm on it.
[Train roars]
SYKES: He's gone by now.
I looked every place you told me
to look and I didn't see him.
I'm telling you.
If he was in the hospital.
I would have found him.
So what do you want me to do?
Hold on. Wait a minute.
I marked him. I got him now.
Dr. Alexander Lentz.
"A noted pathologist
at Chicago Memorial Hospital...
"...was walking to his daily tennis match
when an unidentified vehicle...
"...slammed his body...
"...into the barriers that separate
the Drive from Lake Michigan."
Yuck!
Sam. you're not going to believe this.
STEVENS: Sykes' records for the past
two years show no calls to Kimble.
It was a thought.
But when I cross-checked
Kimble's phone records. one came up.
Kimble called Sykes...
Get Sykes in here now.
STEVENS: ... on the night of the murder...
...7:30 P. M...
... from his car phone.
Do you have the arrest report on Kimble?
SAM: 7:30 P.M.
STEVENS: 19:30 hours.
They just went in. Sykes is gone.
POOLE: He's nowhere to be found.
He's gone.
[Train roars]
Possible sighting of Richard Kimble
on northbound El coming into Van Buren.
Move to the door. Doc.
INTERCOM: Next stop. Balbo station.
This is my stop.
This is my stop too.
Kimble!
[Loud gun blast]
[Metal wheels screeching]
[Sykes grunting]
[Sykes groans and yells]
You missed your stop.
[Loud thud]
[Violent shattering]
Sam. Sam.
A transit cop spotted Kimble on the EI.
he is heading toward Balbo.
The C.P.D. Is on the way.
[Chopper humming]
[Sirens wailing]
C. B: Attention all units. Transit police
report officer down at Balbo Station.
C. B: Kimble is suspect.
Repeat officer down.
What'd he do. shoot a cop?
COSMO: Chicago P.D. Will eat him alive.
HOST: It is a joy and a privilege...
to introduce tonight's keynote speaker.
For the past four years...
...he has served as
the A. Jude Robinson Fellow...
...and Administrative Chief of Pathology...
... at Chicago Memorial Hospital.
Where are the emergency exits?
C. B: Suspect seen entering
Hilton Tower Mall. lower level. Repeat...
COSMO: You don't think...
I know where he's going.
COSMO: Biggs. Newman. where are you?
He was appointed
to the Board of Directors...
...of Devlin MacGregor Pharmaceuticals.
You all please give a warm welcome...
...to Dr. Charles Nichols.
[Applause]
Thank you very much.
ladies and gentlemen...
...my friends and colleagues.
CHARLES: It's great you're all here tonight.
[Sirens blare. tires screech]
NEWMAN: C.P.D. Reported an officer down
and a guy with two guns...
SAM: Kimble do it?
BIGGS: Conflicting reports.
He entered the hotel from the subway.
SAM: That's my man!
ROSETTl: Not anymore.
He's going down.
You can help by staying out.
Arrest us!
SAM: Lock it up! Start at the lower level.
All units report when lower level is secure.
All units. secure all lower level exits.
Noah. go and find the hotel security office.
Stay in touch with me on the radio.
CHARLES: Now. a new drug...
... on the cusp of approval
by the Food and Drug Administration...
... is poised to change
these old methods forever.
Deputy Newman. U.S. Marshal's Service.
Sam. I'm in.
... through the normal metabolic pathways
in the liver.
The drug's name is...
...Provasic.
CHARLES: As I will show you tonight...
...Provasic is remarkably effective...
... and has no side effects whatsoever.
It is also noteworthy that this drug...
...that this drug was developed...
... in cooperation. not competition
with Chicago Memorial Hospital...
... in what we hope will be...
...the model for a continued dishonest...
...excuse me. honest...
... open joint venture...
...between academic medicine...
... and the pharmaceutical industry...
Richard!
I'm sorry. I'm in the middle of this speech.
You almost got away with it.
I know all about it.
I can prove it.
Ladies and gentlemen. my friend.
Richard Kimble. doesn't feel well...
CHARLES: ... obviously...
... so if you just go on
with your dessert and coffee...
Richard. would you step aside
and let's talk.
So I'll be back in just a second.
You changed the samples. didn't you?
You switched the samples...
...after Lentz died.
HOST: Let's stay calm. people.
After Lentz died. you were
the only one who had access.
You switched the samples...
...and the pathology reports.
You killed Lentz too?
Call Security.
RICHARD: Did you?
He falsified his research...
...so RDU-90 could be...
...approved and...
...Devlin MacGregor
could give you Provasic.
HOST: All right. it's all over. folks.
Let's just stay calm.
[Propellers pelting]
[Loud crash]
You never give up. Richard. do you?
You never give up!
[Groaning]
Why Helen?
SECURITY GUARD: Glad you're here.
Which way'd they go?
GUARD: Toward the Presidential Suite.
SAM: Where's that?
GUARD: Southeast corner.
SAM: How many exits
are there in this room?
We got a total of four:
Two on the east. two on the west.
NEWMAN: Kimble's on the roof!
Cosmo. that way.
PILOT ON O VERHEAD RADIO:
Stop! Stay where you are!
This is the Chicago police!
Put your hands in the air!
The building is totally secure.
I repeat. do not move!
Put your hands in the air!
I repeat. stay where you are!
Talk to me.
They're headed to the north end
of the roof.
SAM: Newman!
Get that helicopter out of here!
As soon as you get a clean shot...
...you take him out.
[Multiple rifle blasts]
Newman. get rid of the helicopter!
NEWMAN: Why?
SAM: Because I don't want to get shot!
C.P.D.. there's a U.S. Marshal
out on the roof. Hold your fire!
NEWMAN: Call off the helicopter!
[Painful groan]
[Violent shattering]
[Loud crashing]
[Machine buzzing]
Don't shoot.
COSMO: This guy ever quit?
Find out where that elevator stops.
Newman. Northwest elevator!
Where does it stop?
Where did they go? Where did they go?
GUARD: Stopped on the 5th floor.
NEWMAN: They're on the 5th floor.
NEWMAN: What's on the 5th floor?
GUARD: It's the laundry.
NEWMAN: They stopped at the laundry.
[Breathing heavily]
[Steam hissing]
COSMO: We're on the 5th floor.
What's your 20?
BIGGS: It's right behind you.
BIGGS: What the hell is going on here?
You got to keep the C.P.D. Out.
They're much too hot to suit me.
I want you to get rid of all these people.
POOLE: Okay. people. stay calm.
SAM: Cosmo. come with me.
[Steam hissing]
SAM: Dr. Richard Kimble!
There's no way out of here. Richard!
SAM: The entire building is locked down!
Give it up. you don't have any time!
SAM: Chicago Police Department thinks
you're a cop killer!
SAM: They will shoot you on sight!
SAM: Richard. I know you're innocent!
I know about Fredrick Sykes!
SAM: I know about Dr. Charles Nichols!
SAM: Richard. he borrowed your car
the night of your wife's murder!
SAM: He had the keys!
SAM: No forced entry. Richard.
SAM: He telephoned Sykes
from your car. Richard!
SAM: Richard. give it up!
SAM: I'm either lying to you
or I'm going to shoot you!
SAM: What do you think?
Give it up! It's time to stop running!
[Loud yelp]
[Groaning]
[Buzzer ringing in distance]
[Steam hissing]
They killed my wife.
I know it. Richard.
I know it.
But. it's over now.
[Sighing] You know. I'm glad.
I need the rest.
[Chaotic yelling]
REPORTER 1: Who killed Kimble's wife?
KELLY: Kimble was convicted of it.
REPORTER 2:
You've got a one-armed man in custody.
REPORTER 2: Is that the guy?
KELLY: I have no idea.
REPORTER 1:
How many one-armed men are there?
KELLY: There're a lot of them.
REPORTER 1:
Could you have made a mistake?
[Flashbulb popping]
ROSETTl: You got a deadline.
play the weather again.
COSMO: Tell Samuel Gerard I'm going
home now. I'm taking my vacation.
POOLE: Clear this area. Everybody clear.
[Chaotic yelling]
BIGGS: Watch your head.
Poole. where is that thing?
Let me see those hands. Doctor.
I thought you didn't care.
I don't.
[Chuckling]
Don't tell anybody. okay?
Subtitles conformed by SOFTITLER